<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Dominique Girard, Psy.D/Ph.D</title><link>https://dominiquegirard.com/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Dominique Girard, Psy.D/Ph.D</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>dominique.girard@radboudumc.nl (Dominique Girard, Psy.D/Ph.D)</managingEditor><webMaster>dominique.girard@radboudumc.nl (Dominique Girard, Psy.D/Ph.D)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominiquegirard.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://dominiquegirard.com/page/publications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>dominique.girard@radboudumc.nl (Dominique Girard, Psy.D/Ph.D)</author><guid>https://dominiquegirard.com/page/publications/</guid><description>Articles (peer-reviewed) Girard, D., Tuinema, M., van Wijngaarden, E. (2025). The meaning of suffering in the context of euthanasia and assisted suicide: A Meta-Ethnography. Mortality. https://doi.org/10.1080/13576275.2025.2509510
Thölking, T. W., Girard, D., Engels, Y., Schoon, Y., Van Wijngaarden, E. (2025). Considerations of older adults with multimorbidity when facing healthcare choices: a qualitative systematic review. Patient Education and Counseling. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2025.109194
Girard, D., Van Zutven, M., Van Wijngaarden, E. (2025). Dying in the Margins: A Hermeneutical and Phenomenological Reflection on Liminality and Paradoxes.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://dominiquegirard.com/page/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>dominique.girard@radboudumc.nl (Dominique Girard, Psy.D/Ph.D)</author><guid>https://dominiquegirard.com/page/about/</guid><description>Why studying Death and Dying? Philosophers and theologians around the globe have recognized a certain value to death in life. Death and life are bound together. Death brings new ideas and new ways through generational changes of values and ideals. Death also reminds us of our vulnerability, finitude and our resemblance as humans sharing the same fate.
However, in our contemporary western society, the outlook on death has changed, with increased control over the end-of-life journey.</description></item></channel></rss>